Martin Haensch, B.Eng.

Menlo Park, CA ✓ Eligibility: Eligible to work in the U.S. Personal website: https://mhansch.com/

haenschmartin@gmail.com 🖂

+1 (650) 223-3141

https://www.linkedin.com/in/martin-haensch/

SUMMARY

I am a motivated, reliable and dedicated German automation engineer and a full stack software developer with 4+ years of professional experience in the field of renewable energy systems. I successfully launched my first self-developed PLC control web application "smart.ModoCorrente" on the German market in 2019. I recently moved to the US and am now looking for new professional challenges and development opportunities as a Software Engineer in the Bay Area.

EDUCATION

THM, Germany **University of Applied Science Mittelhessen**

10/2014 - 05/2018

- **Degree**: B. Eng. (Electrical and Information Technology)
- Major: Automation Engineering
- Programming Coursework: Algorithms and data structures, Web Development, Databases

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Entrepreneur & Software Engineer In cooperation with TeDatCo, Germany

05/2018 - 08/2020

smart.ModoCorrente: Web-based PLC controlling system

- Documenting and managing the entire project including training external staff
- Developing and programming of a functional PLC (S7-1200) that connects to an external server with minimal data
- Designing and programming of external interfaces to manage the connections of the external PLCs and to receive
- Administering and organizing No-SQL database relationships between multiple clients
- Programming a customer-friendly website to control PLC outputs and display current data
- General Information: Launched in the German market in 2019, the product optimizes maintenance while reducing wind turbine downtime

Utilized: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, PHP, C#, MongoDB, TIA Portal, SCL, TCP/IP, Git

Electrical Engineer

TeDatCo GmbH, Germany

05/2018 - 08/2020

ModoCorrente (www.modoCorrente.de): System for remote control for renewable energy (wind, solar)

- Planning and installing control systems for renewable energy components (e.g., wind turbines)
- Preparing technical drawings and Handling circuit diagrams to ensure projects fit regulations and customers' expectations.
- Designing of PLCs (S7-1200), selection of electrical components, wiring and testing of functionality
- Mounting control cabinet including on-site troubleshooting

Utilized: TIA Portal, SPlan, MS Visio, Antenna technology, GSM, Bus Protocols, Glass fiber technologies

External Data Analyst

Philipps University Marburg, Germany

01/2017 - 01/2018

- Preparing and processing physiological data, e.g. with excel
- Scripting and facilitating data management for research staff

Utilized: MS Excel, VBA

Student Trainee

TeDatCo GmbH, Germany

10/2015 - 05/2018

Energy Timetable: VBA programmed automatic timetable.

- Programming of a VBA-Excel application for a large industrial food retailer (www.gemuese-meyer.de)
- General information: The application automatically creates an energy timetable; this is necessary in Germany for large companies to insure the grid stability

Utilized: MS Excel, VBA

Vocational Training / Office Manager PMCS GmbH & Co. KG, Germany 08/2009 - 06/2012 Military Service (First-Aid Department) German Military, Germany 07/2007 - 05/2009

PRIVATE PROJECTS

"Bartists" (in progress): Platform to connect bars and artists

Full stack web development project including frontend, backend and the design Utilized: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.js, PHP, Laravel, MySQL

"Plantguard" (smart home application): Controller to water plants automatically

Programming a NodeESP-Board with sensors and actors to water plants automatically Utilized: Arduino Software, C